-=北理FTP联盟字幕组=-
作品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=北理FTP联盟字幕组=-
作品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
But this film isn't about Adam.
但这部片子，并不是关于Adam
So this is the table saw.
lt was spinning that way...
就是这台锯 那个时候它正这样转着...
(man) this is Rick.
这位是Rick.
...and it was that quick.
...它就是那么快
So that's why l gotta keep working.
Until l die.
这就是为什么我继续工作 直到我死掉
OK.
OK
l always gotta keep my ears open
because there's always spillages.
我总得仔细听着 哪些地方会撒出东西来
Sometimes you get a gallon of milk.
有时候是一加仑的牛奶
Tomato sauce - oh, you're in trouble.
lt'll take a half-hour to clean that up.
番茄酱 哦，麻烦来了 要花费半个小时来清理干净
And l look up on every aisle
so as everything is clean.
我得检查每条过道保证一切都干干净净
lf l see something l pick it up,
whether it's paper or garbage.
如果我看到地上有什么东西我必须得捡起来  不管是垃圾还是纸屑
And l had to climb in there
to get the keys out.
结果我只好爬进去，把钥匙拿出来
lt's a sad situation.
那就很倒霉了
lf there are golden years,
l can't find 'em, l'll tell you that.
如果有什么黄金时代 是找不到的，我会告诉你的...
She had a painkiller for her hip.
她原来有治屁股的止痛药
The girl said, ''Frank, this is $ 21 3.''
''What, for a painkiller?''
女孩说"Frank,这个213美元" "什么,止痛药？"
- l didn't take it.
- l backed off. l said, ''l gotta come back.''
- 我就不要了   - 我走了，我说"我得回去"
What's in them? What's in these
new drugs that they distribute?
都是些什么啊? 他们给开的新药都是什么啊
l don't believe you need
half of the things they tell you.
我认为 他们告诉你的近一半的东西都根本不需要
l have never taken medication now,
as l'm getting older.
现在我从不吃药 我正在变老
l don't even like to take an aspirin.
我甚至连阿司匹林都不吃了
l do like a little brandy.
我更愿意来点儿白兰地
Paramedics got her out of the car and into
an ambulance for a trip to the hospital.
医护人员把她从车里救出来，用救护车送进了医院
l get a bill from my insurance company
我从保险公司收到了一张账单
告诉我他们不会支付救护车的费用
telling me that the ambulance ride
was not going to be paid for,
告诉我他们不会支付救护车的费用
because it wasn't preapproved.
因为这不在预批的项目当中
l should have grabbed my cellphone
off the street and called in the ambulance?
我该拿起我掉在路上的手机 在我到救护车之前打个电话?
l mean, it's just crazy.
我的意思是，这太离谱了
(woman) l applied for
HealthNet insurance for Jason.
我给Jason申请了一份健康网上的保险
They rejected him
because of his height and weight.
他们因为他的身高和体重而拒绝了
l applied for healthcare
through BlueCross BlueShield
我申请BlueCross BlueShield的健康保险
So I posted a note on the internet.
所以我在互联网上发了一个帖子
about problems
with their insurance company.
关于他们保险公司的问题的
had sent me
their healthcare horror stories.
给我发来了他们的医保恐怖经历
Some of them decided
not to wait for me to get back to them.
他们中的一些人决定不等我回复他们
His daughter was nine months old when
they discovered she was going deaf.
他女儿在9个月大的时候被发现她就要聋了
His health insurance company.
CIGNA.
他的健康保险公司,CIGNA
said they'd pay for an implant
in only one of her ears.
说他们只能给她支付一只耳朵植入助听器的钱
According to the letter they sent.
根据他们发来的信件
it's experimental
for her to hear in two ears.
让她能够在双耳听到声音，这是实验性质的
lf a cochlear implant
is good for one ear,
如果耳蜗助听器能够在一边耳朵好用
it doesn't even make any sense that
it wouldn't be good for the second ear.
无疑在另一边耳朵里也好用
Especially when a child
is just starting to learn how to talk,
特别对于一个刚刚准备开始学说话的孩子来说
she has to learn
from both sides of her head.
她必须通过她的两只耳朵来学习
This is to ClGNA.
''Noted filmmaker Michael Moore
这是写给CIGNA的信： "著名制片人Michael Moore
''l've sent information concerning ClGNA's
lack of caring for its policy holders.''
我将关于CIGNA疏于照顾它的 客户的信息发了过去
''Has your CEO ever been
in a film before?''
你们的CEO上过电影吗？
(Moore) Before he knew it. he received
a call on his voice mail from CIGNA.
在他知道之前， 他就收到了来自CIGNA总部的语音邮件
(answerphone) tuesday. 8.:54 am.
星期二 上午8:54
【CIGNA总部】
Hi Noe先生， 我是来自CIGNA医疗保险公司的Edward
我跟你说下关于Annete的事情
有个好消息：
专家的复诊结果出来了
专家们一致否定了之前的决定
同时证明了装第二个助听器的重要性，厄，
耳蜗助听器
谢谢你
Obviously all this worked because Annette
is going to get her second implant in July.
很明显，成功了  因为Annette将在7月植入她的第二只助听器
(woman) ''Dear Mike.
I work in the industry. ''
你好，Mike，我在这个行业供职...
(woman #2) ''I work for an HMO. ''
我为卫生维护组织（HMO）工作...
(Moore) I started to get hundreds of letters
of a different sort
我开始收到上千封各样的信
from people who work inside
the healthcare industry.
都是在医保行业工作的人写的
(man #2) ''Health insurance
companies suck. Flat suck. ''
"健康保险公司真逊，绝对的逊"
(Moore) Like Becky Malke. who was
in charge of keeping sick people away
就像Becky Malke他主要负责拒绝病人
from one of America's
top insurance companies.
来自美国顶级保险公司之一
我在一个电话中心工作,人们打电话过来要求支取保险金
(Becky) l work in a call center, so people
call in and ask for insurance quotes.
我在一个电话中心工作,人们打电话过来要求支取保险金
There are certain preexisting conditions,
basically industry-wide,
有一些预先规定的症状，基本上，整个行业
diabetes, heart disease,
certain forms of cancer.
糖尿病、心脏病、某些癌症
lf you have these conditions, you are likely
not going to get your health insurance.
如果你有这些症状，你几乎不可能拿到你的保险金
(Moore) How long is this list of conditions
that make you ineligible?
那份让你拿不成保险金的列表有多长？
lt would be a really long list.
lt would be a long list.
那是个非常长的列表，非常长...
如果你有以下疾病
你将拿不到医疗保险
Sometimes you know they're gonna
be declined at the end of the application,
有时你预先就能知道 在最后他们的申请会被拒绝
and they're like...
God, like one time l had a couple,
他们就像... 天哪，有一次，我接待了一对夫妇
and they were so happy to get...
l'm gonna cry.
他们对于能拿到...是如此的高兴 我要苦了...
They were so happy that they were...
l took them through this application.
他们是那么高兴，他们... 我帮他们进行了申请
And the wife said to him,
''Don't worry, baby, it's gonna be OK.''
然后妻子说"宝贝别担心，一切都会OK的"
And when l looked, l could tell
they were gonna get declined
当我看到他们的申请表的时候， 我可以告诉，他们会被拒绝
l thought, ''God, they're gonna get
that call in a couple of weeks
我想"天啊他们过两个星期就会接到那个电话"
l just felt so bad
'cause l just really thought
我难受极了因为我真的想
and l knew
and l couldn't say anything to them.
也知道，我不能对他们说任何事情
because l don't wanna
get to know them,
因为我不想认识他们，我不想...
l don't wanna know about their lives,
l just wanna get in and out,
我不想了解他们的生活 我仅仅想上班、下班
(Moore) In spite of Becky being
a bit of a pain on the phone.
不管Becky在电话前是如何的痛苦
a quarter billion Americans
are still able to get health insurance.
2亿5千万美国人 仍然能够获得健康保险
Let's meet some of these
happy insured customers.
让我们来看看这些快乐的有保险的客户
And Diane. Horizon BlueCross.
Diane. Horizon有BlueCross
BCS insures Laurel.
BCS对Laurel保险
And Caroline has CIGNA.
Caroline有CIGNA
1971年2月17号 下午5:23
Ehrlichman(政治顾问): 我们现在来仔细研究下副总统在这件事上的问题
第一个问题，我们是否应该包括...
美国健康保险计划就像Edgar Kaiser的永久计划那样
Nixon(美国总统):现在我问你...
你知道我对这些医疗项目不是太苛刻
这是一个私人企业项目
恩，这倒挺诱人的
Edgar Kaiser正在做这个有利可图的项目
他能一直做下去的原因是...
我曾让Edgar Kaiser过来跟我谈过这件事
我似乎想得太多了
所有的激励措施反而使 人们得到的医疗保健更少了
不过正因为如此 提供的医疗保健越少，他们越能从中获利
很好
激励措施很有效
不错
第二天，1971年2月18日
不，我的手受伤了
这条路下面就有一家医院
∮我们种好我们的麦子∮
∮因为劳动最光荣∮
∮但凭我们谦卑的努力∮
∮一定能带领我们获得丰收∮
∮我们不会拒绝∮
∮我们答到:我们能用好它∮
∮丰收!丰收!继续装,继续装∮
∮指标已经完成∮
∮我们是消防员∮
∮我们拯救生命∮
∮即使是树上的小猫∮
∮我们是美国的教师∮
∮让美国的孩子们享受义务教育∮
∮我们是邮政服务人员∮
∮让你们能享受低廉的邮件服务∮
∮这是图书馆∮
∮这里你们能免费借书∮
But l think we live comfortably here.
但是我认为我们在这过的很舒服.
London is expensive,
but l think we live comfortably.
伦敦消费很高,但是我觉得我们过的很舒服.
You're getting by OK on the million-dollar
home, the Audi, and the flat-screen TV?
百万美圆的房子,奥迪,还有平板电视， 你觉得一切都很好了?
Yeah, we're coping with those.
是的,这些就可以了.
l think democracy is the most
revolutionary thing in the world.
我认为民主政治是这 世界上最具革命性的事情.
Far more revolutionary than
socialist ideas, or anybody else's idea.
比社会主义,还是任何人的 想法，都要具革命性.
Because if you have power, you use it
to meet the needs of your community.
因为如果你有了能力,你可以用它来给你的团体争取利益.
And this idea of choice which capital
talks about, ''you've got to have a choice,''
这个选择的概念就像首府谈论的,''你必须要有一个选择,''
choice depends
on the freedom to choose.
有了选择的自由才有 选择的机会.
lf you're shackled with debt,
you don't have a freedom to choose.
如果你债务缠身,你就 没有了选择的自由.
(Moore) lt seems it benefits the system if
the average person is shackled with debt.
看起来要是人人都 债务缠身了那么收益的将会是组织.
People in debt become hopeless,
and hopeless people don't vote.
负债的人变的绝望,绝望的人不会投票.
They always say
everyone should vote,
他们一直在说人人都有权投票,
but l think if the poor in Britain
or the United States
但是我想要是英国的或者美国的穷人
voted for people
who represented their interests,
给能代表他们利益的人投票,
it would be a real democratic revolution.
那才会是场真正的民主革命.
So they don't want it to happen. So keeping
people hopeless and pessimistic...
他们不会让这一切发生的. 所以继续让人们感到绝望，悲观...
See, l think there are two ways
in which people are controlled.
我认为控制民众有两种方法.
First of all, frighten people,
and secondly, demoralize them.
第一种,让他们恐慌,第二种,让他们受挫.
An educated, healthy and confident
nation is harder to govern.
一个有着良好教育的,健康的， 自信的国家是很难驾御的.
And l think there's an element
in the thinking of some people:
而且我认为有些人会这样想:
''We don't want people to be
educated, healthy and confident,
''我们不希望人们都接受 良好教育,并且健康自信，
because they would get out of control.''
因为这些人会摆脱控制.''
The top 1 % of the world's population
own 80% of the world's wealth.
全世界1%的人口掌握着80%的财富.
lt's incredible that people put up with it,
but they're poor,
人民能够忍受这个实在太难以 置信了,但他们是穷人,
they're demoralized, they're frightened.
他们受挫了,他们太恐慌了.
And therefore, they think
perhaps the safest thing to do
因此,他们认为可能最安全的
is to take orders and hope for the best.
就是老实的接受并且怀揣希望.
(Moore) And hope for the best
is what we do.
怀揣希望正是我们所做的.
right from the moment we're born.
打我们出生的那一刻起就是.
We've got the worst infant mortality rate
in the western world.
在西方国家里我们有着最糟糕的婴儿死亡率.
A baby born in El Salvador
has a better chance of surviving
萨尔瓦多新生儿的存活率都要比
than a baby born in Detroit.
底特律的高.
But it gets better
when we go to school.
但是进入学校以后情况要好点.
(man #9) Classrooms with 40 students.
schools with no labs.
一个班40人. 没有图书馆.
(Moore) No wonder the majority
of our adults can't find Britain on a map.
毫无疑问我们大多数的 成年人在地图上找不到英国.
But that's OK.
There's always college.
但是没关系. 总会有大学.
By the time we graduate.
our ass is so in hock.
我们毕业的时候. 就已经陷入债务牢笼.
we're in debt before our first job.
我们在还没找到第一份工作时候 就负债累累.
l'm at about... we'll say about $35,000
in debt. That's for my third year in college.
我大概...大概负债$35,000.  那是我大学3年级的时候.
(Moore) You'll be the employee they're
looking for - one who needs this job.
你将会被他们雇佣 因为你需要这份工作.
3,904, 3,905...
3904,3905...
What employer wouldn't employ someone
thousands of dollars in debt.
哪个老板不愿雇佣欠债数千美圆的员工.
because they won't cause any trouble?
因为他们不会惹任何麻烦?
In addition to paying off your college debt.
you need a job with health insurance.
除了要还你大学时期欠下的债务.  你得找一份能提供健康保险的工作.
It would be horrible
to lose that job. wouldn't it?
要是丢掉那样一份工作 简直不敢想象. 不是吗?
You can always quit, you know. There's
no law that says you have to work here.
想什么时候离开都行,你知道的.  没有法律规定你必须在这工作.
(Moore) If that one job
doesn't pay all the bills. don't worry.
如果那份工作支付 不了所有的帐单. 别担心.
You can get another one.
and another one. and another one.
你可以再找一份. 然后再找一份. 然后再找一份.
l work three jobs,
and l feel like l contribute.
我干三份工作,我感到对社会很有贡献.
- You work three jobs?
- Three jobs, yes.
- 你干三分工作?  - 三份工作,是的.
Uniquely American, isn't it? l mean,
that is fantastic that you're doing that.
少见的美国人,不是吗?  我是说,你那样做太不可思议了.
Get any sleep?
睡觉吗?
(Moore) If you're not sleeping.
take pharmaceuticals.
如果你失眠. 那就吃药吧.
(man #1 0) You're tired all the time.
You feel sad.
你时刻都感到疲劳. 感到悲哀
(woman #8) If you suffer
from excessive worry...
如果你陷入过度的烦恼...
(woman #9) Generalized anxiety disorder.
泛焦虑症.
(woman #1 0) It could be adult ADD.
那可能是"成人注意缺失紊乱".
- (woman #1 1) Ask your doctor.
- (man #1 1) Ask your doctor.
- 去看医生.  - 去看医生.
(Moore) Yes. ask your doctor.
and ask him for more drugs.
是的.去看医生. 找他要更多的药品.
That should keep you doped up
until it's time to retire.
那会让你形成依赖直到退休.
Did I say retire? (laughs)
我有说退休吗?
If you make it to 80.
your pension will still be there.
如果你能一直干到80岁. 你会一直有养老金.
unlike the new employees for these
companies. who'll never see a pension.
不象这些公司新来的员工.  永远不会看到一分钱养老金.
But I'm sure our kids will take care of us.
considering the great life we've given 'em.
考虑到我们给予他们伟大的生命,但是我确信我们孩子会照顾我们的.
Remember. let's defeat the terrorists over
there so we don't have to fight them here.
记住. 先让我们打败那些小恐怖分子吧， 那样我们就不用担心现在这些了
Kaiser Permanente
is the largest HMO in the country.
Kaiser Permanente是国家最大的卫生保健组织.
And Dawnelle Keyes was fortunate
enough to be fully insured by them.
Dawnelle Keyes足够有钱而成为他们的保户.
It's a good thing. because one night.
her 1 8-month-old daughter. Mychelle.
这是件好事. 因为一天晚上. 她18个月大的女儿. Mychelle.
developed a fever of over 1 0 4.
高烧超过了104度（40摄氏度）.
So. like any responsible mom.
she called 9 1 1.
所以. 像所有有责任心的妈妈一样. 她拨了911.
and the ambulance took Mychelle
to the closest hospital.
救护车把Mychelle送去了最近的医院.
The hospital checked with her HMO
医院查看了她的HMO（美国保健组织）保险
and they were told that Kaiser would not
cover the tests and the antibiotics
然后他们被告知在Kaiser公司的保险里 不包括各种检查费用和必要抗生素
necessary to treat Mychelle.
来治疗Mychelle.
She would have to take her to
an in-network. Kaiser-owned hospital.
她得带着女儿去一家联网内的. Kaiser公司下属医院.
Kaiser said that l should
bring her by car to the hospital,
Kaiser公司让我带着她去另家医院,
and that she shouldn't be treated
at Martin Luther King.
她不会被马丁路德金医院接收治疗.
l just continued to ask them
to treat her, and they refused.
我不断的请求他们治疗,但是他们拒绝了.
My daughter got worse
and she had a seizure.
我女儿的病加重了还有癫痫症状
(Moore) Dawnelle begged doctors to not
listen to Kaiser and to treat her daughter.
Dawnelle求医生不要听Kaiser公司的， 先医治她女儿.
l was escorted out of the hospital
because they felt that l was a threat.
我被请出了医院因为 他们觉得我是个威胁.
(Moore) After hours of delay.
she was transported to Kaiser.
耽搁大概一小时之后.  她被转到了Kaiser公司下属医院.
and got there just in time
to go into cardiac arrest.
刚到那心脏就停止跳动了.
They worked on her for about 30 minutes,
trying to revive her.
他们花了30分钟,试图能挽救她.
And the doctors came in
and let us know that she had expired.
然后医生出来告诉 我她已经断气了.
l was in a daze, a real daze.
lt just didn't seem real.
我晕了,真的晕了.  一切就像是幻觉.
l just held her.
我抱着她.
l held her and l told her
that Mommy tried her best to help her,
我抱着她告诉她妈妈已经尽力了,
to make sure that she was gonna
get the treatment she needed to receive.
已经尽力让她得到应有的治疗.
And that l was sorry
that l wasn't able to help her.
还有很遗憾没能够帮助到他.
(toy) Simon says.: give the answer.
快回答.
( computerized tune)
Uh-oh.
啊-噢.
(Moore) This is Karena
and her daughter Zoe.
这是Karena和她的女儿Zoe.
Karena is a graduate
of Michigan State University.
Karena毕业于Michigan州立大学.
and a native of my hometown
of Flint. Michigan.
我的家乡Flint（Michigan州）长大..
Six months ago. Zoe.
like Dawnelle's baby Mychelle.
6个月前. Zoe.  和Dawnelle的孩子Mychelle一样.
came down with a high fever.
发了高烧.
What happened
is she stopped breathing for a little while,
她有一会停止呼吸了,
turned blue and passed out
in my arms, which was...
脸色发青,昏在我怀里...
lt was the most horrible moment
in my life, l think,
我想这是我一生中最可怕的时刻,
just because l thought
that she was either dead or dying.
因为我觉得她已经死了 或者是正走向死亡.
And l had no clue what to do.
还有我不知道应该干嘛.
At the hospital, they gave her
some medicine to bring the fever down,
在医院,他们给她吃退烧药,
and examined her, took some blood.
做检查,抽了点血.
- (Moore) What was wrong with her?
- lt was a throat infection.
-  她是怎么了?  - 喉咙发炎.
But we stayed at the hospital
from Friday to Sunday,
我们在医院一直从星期五呆到了星期天,
- just so they could keep an eye on her.
- You stayed there that long?
- 要有人看着她.  - 你呆了那么长时间?
Yeah. They just basically
kept an eye on her.
是的. 得有个人照顾她.
And how much did all this cost you,
the three-plus days in the hospital?
这一共花了你多少钱,在医院的三天?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
- 没花钱.  -没花钱?
- Nothing. Nothing at all.
- And that's because?
- 是的. 一分钱也没花.  - 那是因为?
- l live in France.
- You live in France?
- 我住法国.  - 你住法国?
Yeah.
是的.
(Moore) Ah. France.
啊.法国.
They enjoy their wine.
their cigarettes and their fatty foods.
他们享受美酒.香烟还有美食.
And yet.
just like the Canadians and the Brits.
还有. 就像加拿大人和英国人一样.
they live much longer than we do.
他们比我们更长寿.
Something about that
seemed grossly unfair.
似乎不怎么公平.
This is Alexi Cremieux.
这是Alexi Cremieux.
He spent his entire adult life in the US
without health insurance.
他在美国没有健康保险 过了整个成人时期.
(Alexi) l lived in America for 1 3 years.
l loved my life there.
我在美国. 我喜欢那儿的生活.
But then when l discovered that l had
a tumor and l didn't have health insurance,
但是当我发现我得了肿瘤 而且我没有健康保险,
unfortunately,
l had to come back here.
很不幸,我得回来.
Even though l had never paid taxes
in France 'cause l never worked here -
尽管在法国我从来没交过税， 因为我没在这工作过
l left when l was 1 8,
l had no Social Security number -
我18岁就离开了,我没有社会保险编号
for them it was,
''He needs treatment, he has no income,
对他们来说,''他需要治疗,他没有收入,
so we're gonna give him,
you know, the treatment he needs.''
所以我们准备给他,你知道,他需要接受治疗.''
- (Moore) How are you doing now?
- l'm healthy now,
- 你现在如何了?  - 痊愈了,
but l had three months
of chemotherapy.
但是我有过3个月的化疗.
So after three months, l saw my doctor
and he said, ''You wanna go back to work?''
所以3个月以后,医生对我说,''你想回去工作吗?''
l said, ''No, l don't feel like it.''
我说,''不,我感觉不太好.''
''Right now, l'm not ready.''
He said, ''How much do you need?''
''现在,我还没准备好.'' 他说,''你需要多少钱?''
l said, ''Well, l don't know.''
He said, ''Would three months be OK?''
我说,''我不知道''  他说,''3个月行吗?''
l said, ''l think three months
would be fine.''
我说,''我觉得3个月不错.''
He said, ''OK, so take three months off.''
So he wrote me a note
他说,''好,那就休息3个月.'' 然后他给我写了张条
that l gave to my employer
to make sure l got paid.
拿着条就可以找老板要工资了.
- So l went to the south of France...
- Wait a minute, three months off with pay?
- 接着我去了法国南部... -等一下,什么也不干也拿了3个月的薪水?
Yes. Yes.
是的. 是的.
l get 65% paid by the government,
政府付我65%,
and then the other 35%
is paid by my employer.
剩下的35%由我老板付.
To make sure you get 1 00%.
确保你能拿到全部工资.
So it was April, it was spring again. So
l started right away, sucking up some sun.
那时候是四月,又是春天了.  所以我立刻动身,去吸收阳光.
And that really helped me a lot,
to recharge my batteries.
而且这真的帮助了我很多,让我涣然一新.
l mean, it was like night and day. ln three
months, l went from a 95-year-old man
我是说,就好象做梦一样. 3个月的时间,我从一个95岁的老人
to a 35-year-old man again.
重新回到了35岁.
But that's because l had that time
to take care of myself.
那完全是因为我有时间照顾自己.
l'm not in a position to make any judgment
concerning the American system.
我并不是在评价 美国的制度怎么样.
l think the United States
is a great, great country.
我觉得美利坚真是一个伟大,很伟大的国家.
Americans are great people.
l really love them.
美国人很棒.  我真的很喜欢他们.
But as a doctor first, as a citizen second,
但是首先做为一个医生,其次一个公民,
and eventually, as a patient third,
最后,作为一个病人,
l'm very glad to be in France.
我很高兴我在法国.
lt's kind of a luxury here.
这儿简直有些奢侈.
You are sick, you step in a hospital,
you get the care you need.
如果你病了,走进一家医院,你就会得到治疗.
lt doesn't depend on your premiums.
lt depends on what you need.
这与你的保险费无关. 而是在于你需要什么.
One of the principles is solidarity.
其中一个原则是团结.
People who are better off
pay for those who are worse off.
那些经济状况好的人给那些不富裕的人付钱.
You pay according to your means
and you receive according to your needs.
按照你的方式来付钱,按你的需要来取得.
(Moore) Do you think
that will ever work in America?
你认为这在美国可行吗?
No.
不行.
(Moore) He could barely contain
his seething anti-Americanism.
他几乎不能控制他那沸腾的反美精神.
And I just didn't want
to listen to any more of it.
我不想再听下去了.
So I found a group of Americans
currently living in Paris.
所以我找了一批我认识的.
who I know would tell me the truth.
现在居住在巴黎的美国人来告诉我真相.
l was diagnosed five years ago
with Type l diabetes.
五年前我被诊断出患有1型糖尿病.
- l was a bit nervous to tell them l had...
- (Moore) To tell the French?
- 我有一点儿的紧张去告诉他们我有... - 告诉那些法国人?
There's a place to check off
if you have a chronic condition.
有一个地方可以让你去核对是否患有慢性疾病.
l was nervous that they
were going to charge me more.
我害怕他们会让我支付更多的金钱.
And instead, l went into a hospital,
and had round-the-clock care.
相反的,我去了一家医院做了全天候的检查.
And they do an amazing amount
of preventative care.
他们在预防性的检查上做了数量惊人的工作.
They asked if you have
a preexisting condition,
他们问我是否有病历史,
not to punish you,
but to give you more help?
不是惩罚你,而是给了你更多的帮助?
- Yes.
- l was in the hospital for a year.
- 是的. - 我在这家医院住了一年.
As soon as l was in, it was,
''Well, don't worry, just rest.''
当我刚住进去的时候,他们告诉我,"好了,别担心,好好休息."
- People said ''Rest.''
- How many sick days do you get a year?
- 他们说 ''休息.'' - 你一年之中的病假有多少天?
- l think it's unlimited.
- Unlimited?
- 我想是无限制的. - 无限制的?
Yes. How can you limit sick days?
lf you're sick, you're sick.
是的.怎么能限制生病的天数呢? 如果你病了,那你就真是病了.
l've gone to emergency rooms
numerous times, with four boys.
我跟四个男孩去过急诊室几次.
And have never waited
more than an hour. Never.
我从来没有等待超过一个小时.从未.
l can call and somebody comes
to the house in half an hour.
我可以打电话过去,医生会在半小时内过来我家里.
No way? Making a house call?
At your place?
不可能吧? 打个电话? 在你自己家里?
How many of you have had
a house call from a doctor? No!
你们有多少人在家里打过电话叫医生过来的? 不可能!
- 3:00am last Friday.
- And how much does this cost you?
- 上星期五上午3点. - 那你付了多少钱?
- Nothing.
- What's this service called?
- 免费的. - 这项服务叫做什么?
急救中心，晚上好
我马上就到
Where are we going?
-我们现在去哪? -第15区
We are going to see a man
who has abdominal pain.
我们去看一个有腹部疼痛的男人.
- Abdominal pain?
- Yeah.
- 腹部疼痛? - 是的.
你呕吐过几次？
2次
我能在你的臀部上打一针么？
恩
急救中心是由 Marcel Lascar医生40年前建立的
Marcel Lascar医生家的水管有问题
就在他家
然后跟一个24小时服务的 水管维修公司打电话
他们派出的水管工 在一小时内就赶到了他家
在一个国家里你能在一个小时内 找到水管工
那医生为什么不能这样呢
我得走了.咱们走吧
- Where do we go next?
- The next visit?
- 接下来我们去哪里? - 下一个患者?
呼叫Bruce
8 L'Arcade街
马上到
( ''L'amour est bleu''
by Vicky Leandros)
( ''爱是蓝色的''--Vicky Leandros)
15分钟前他开始尖叫，因为他小弟弟太疼了
好的
我们现在去21 Turbigo St.
我认为就是感冒...
已经持续24小时了...
还有别的症状么
谢谢你，晚安
l say to anyone who asks me
why l'm in this country
我告诉每一个问我为什么在这个国家的人原因
is that l think it's one of the friendliest
countries that l know of.
那是因为这是我所知的最友善的一个国家.
And talk about family values -
l mean, childcare, healthcare...
谈到家庭价值 我指的是,儿童监护,医疗保健...
We don't pay for day care.
我们不用为托儿所的日托付钱.
The day care where l send my daughter -
and l was a teacher - standards are high.
我女儿的日托费用...我是一名教师 - 我是说这个标准非常高.
So how much does it cost you to have
two children here? How much per hour?
你的两个孩子得付多少钱? 每个小时付多少?
大概每小时1美元
这没什么
(Moore) Are you happy
with how they're cared for?
你对他们受到的照顾感到满意么?
是的，我很满意
他们很专业
受过很好的训练
这里的工作人员虽然不像一个母亲， 但非常亲近
我对他们有自信，满满的
Here, my kids are sure that they are going
to get a certain level of care, education,
在这里,我的孩子收到了一定条件的医疗和教育的照顾,
- college l don't have to worry about...
- (Moore) What do you mean?
- 对于大学,我就不必为此担心了... - 你的意思是?
- lt's free.
- (Moore) You're kidding?
- 免费的. - 你开玩笑的吧?
- You can get a college education for free.
- (Moore) No way.
- 你能免费地获得大学教育.  - 不可能.
- Yes.
- There's not a sense of desperation.
- 真的. - 没有绝望的感觉.
They rest, they enjoy life.
他们休息,他们享受生活.
They spend time with their kids,
there's vacations, family time.
他们花时间去陪他们的孩子,他们有假期,有家庭时间.
- How many weeks of paid vacation?
- Minimum five weeks.
- 有多少带薪休假的时间?  - 至少五个星期.
Five weeks?
Minimum of five weeks?
五个星期? 至少五个星期?
lf you work for a large company,
you get sometimes eight, ten weeks.
如果你在一个大公司工作,一般会有八周到十周的带薪休假.
- Remember that there is a 35-hour week.
- The productivity rate is so high here.
- 记住每周要工作35小时. - 这里的生产力很高.
(Moore) l read it was higher
than the United States.
我听说比美国的还要高.
lf they're working more than 35 hours
a week, they'll get extra days off.
如果他们一周工作超过35小时,会有额外的假期.
That is for part-time
and full-time employees.
对于兼职和全职员工是一样的.
You get five weeks paid vacation
even if you're a part-time employee?
你会有五个星期的带薪休假即使你是兼职员工?
- Of course.
- Everybody.
- 当然. - 每个人都这样.
lf you get married, you get an extra week
or seven days for your honeymoon.
如果你结婚了,你还可以有额外的一周或者七天蜜月假期.
- ln addition to your five weeks.
- You're paid to take your honeymoon?
- 加上你原来的5个星期. - 你们度蜜月都有工资?
Also if you move.
如果你搬家.
You mean if you move
from one apartment to another?
如果你只是从一个住所搬到另外一个呢?
You get one day.
你有一天时间.
- You get a day to move and they pay you?
- These are the laws here.
-你又一天时间去搬家而且他们付你工资? - 这些是这儿的法律规定.
When my daughter was three months old,
they sent somebody to you
当我的女儿三个月大的时候,他们会派人过来
to give you tips on what to do
with your child, every single day, for free.
告诉你一些注意事项比如如何照顾好你的孩子,每天都来,免费的.
And they'll come to your house
and do your laundry!
他们来你家帮你洗衣服!
- They will! Sure!
- No!
- 是的!他们确实这么做的!  - 不!
Stop! Stop!
停! 停!
- When you have a baby.
- 当你有一个小孩的时候. - 当你有一个小孩的时候.
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
我在洗那位母亲给我的衣服
You from the government?
你从政府部门过来的 ?
我受雇于政府
来帮助这些父母
- Can she do anything else?
- lf l want, yes.
- 她还能做其他的吗? - 如果我想的话,是的.
She's, of course,
taking care of the children.
她,当然,照顾孩子.
And l think if l ask her
to prepare a meal for tonight,
我想我让她准备一份晚饭,
she can do it.
她会这么做的.
如果我要你今晚做一顿
胡萝卜大餐，你会做么？
No problem.
没问题.
She's coming twice a week.
她每两个星期来一次.
Four hours a day.
So l can do everything l want,
每天做四小时. 因此我可以做我想做的任何事,
for me, for the house,
for my husband, during four hours.
为我自己,为家庭,为我丈夫,在这四小时之间.
lt's very precious for me.
这对我来说很宝贵.
You don't have any associations?
Nothing to help like that?
你没有像这样的组织帮助你吗?
No. Nobody from the government
comes to your home in America
在美国,如果你是一个新的妈妈
and does your laundry for you,
if you're a new mother.
没有人到你家里来帮你洗衣服.
- lt's difficult.
- Yeah.
- 这样一定很辛苦. - 是的.
(woman #1 2) Something that l experience
a lot of with my own family is guilt.
我在自己家里经历的 一些事情让我现在感到内疚.
Guilt for being here almost,
为我在年轻的时候,
and seeing the advantages and
the benefits l have at such a young age.
就能享受到这样的好处.
Things that my parents worked their whole
life for and haven't come close to touching.
我的父母一辈子都辛勤工作都没有享受到.
lt's really hard
to know that you're here
这真的非常辛苦,让你了解到,
in a very privileged position,
you know, not living the highlife,
自己处于特权的地位,你知道,不是生活在上流社会,
but in comparison, definitely.
And that seems completely unfair.
但是相对来说,明确的. 这看起来非常的不公平.
One of the things
that keeps everything running here
让这些事情在这里发生是由于
is that the government
is afraid of the people.
政府害怕人民.
They're afraid of protests,
they're afraid of reactions from the people.
他们怕人民抗议,他们怕来自于人民的反动.
ln the States, people are afraid of the
government. They're afraid of acting up.
在美国,人们害怕政府. 他们害怕运作不正常.
They're afraid of protesting,
afraid of getting out.
他们不敢抗议,不敢出门.
ln France, that's what people do.
在法国,人们是这样做的.
16万名学生今日参加游行
在Bordeaux 超过2000人参加游行
以争取就业机会和公共服务
我们抗议恶化的工作条件
还有工资!
我们想要什么?
住房!
为谁?
为每一个人!
今天我们希望法律认识到 我们的工作很危险
群众选择集体大喊大叫
"停止工作 给自己放假"
政府规定五旬节要工作
这是不能容忍的
(Moore) Free college education.
free medical care.
免费的大学教育. 免费的医疗保健.
government-issued nannies.
政府雇用的保姆.
I began to wonder
how do they pay for all this?
我开始想他们怎么支付所有的费用?
And then I realized
they're drowning in taxes!
我意识到他们被税务淹没了!
I wanted to see what effect
this would have on a nice French family.
我想看看这会导致怎么的 结果在一个条件比较好的家庭.
so I went to find out.
因此我就去寻找.
- Hello. Welcome.
- Hello. Thank you.
- 你好.欢迎.  - 你好.谢谢.
lt's very nice.
这里真好.
这里是客厅
我们在这喝茶
喝点开胃酒
看看电视
- lt's the news.
- Yes.
- 这是新的.  - 是的.
What is your combined income for
the two of you together for, say one month?
你们俩一共一个月的收入是多少?
我们俩加起来一个月$8,000
All right. You're an engineer
and she's an assistant? Not bad.
好的. 你是工程师,她是助理?不错
这是Anthony的房间,他是最小的孩子
这是Alexander的房间
Alexander,看过来
(Moore) How much is your mortgage?
你们的一个月供房的费用有多少?
$1,575一个月
这是我们的卧室
- (Moore) How many cars do you own?
- Two.
- 你们有几辆汽车? - 2辆.
(Moore) Do you owe money
from medical bills?
你们欠医药费吗?
不，不，我们的医疗系统帮我出了
ls there any other debt? Loans, anything?
你们还有其他债务吗?
不，没有什么债务
- Only the apartment.
- (Moore) What are your other expenses?
- 只有这个房子.  -你们还有其他什么开销吗?
The fish.
鱼.
Fish. Vegetables.
鱼. 蔬菜.
Vegetables are a big
monthly expense for you.
每个月在蔬菜上的花费需要很多?
- Yes. And fruit. Yogurt.
- Yogurt.
- 是的.还有水果,酸奶.   - 酸奶.
What are your other big expenses?
还有什么大笔的费用支出吗?
度假
Very important.
很重要.
这是我们去多米尼加旅游时带回来的
这是我的个人珍藏---我们旅游地的沙子
你瞧，这是从斯里兰卡带回来的
开普敦，南非
埃及
马萨伊马拉，肯尼亚
- (Moore) Kenya?
- We liked.
- 肯尼亚?   - 我们喜欢的.
- (Moore) Are you happy?
- Yes.
- 你开心吗?   - 是的.
你难道说不是？
( ''Je t'aime moi non plus''
by Serge Gainsbourg and Jane Birkin)
( ''我爱你 我也不爱你''--Serge Gainsbourg,Jane Birkin)
(Moore) After seeing all this.
I began to wonder.
在看到这些以后. 我开始想.
Was there a reason
our government and our media
是不是有个理由让我们的政府和媒体
wants us to hate the French?
希望我们恨法国人呢?
Are they worried
we might like the French?
他们担心我们会变得
Or like their ways of doing things?
像法国人那样做事?
It was enough to make me
put away my freedom fries.
这足够让我丢掉我的"自由薯条"了.
Meanwhile. back at home.
同时. 在国内
hospitals had found a new way
to deal with patients
医院找到了一直处理那些
who didn't have health insurance
没有医疗保险
and couldn't pay their bill.
而且付不起医药费的病人.
l was standing against the wall and l saw
a cab do a U-turn and pull up to the curb.
我当时站在墙的对面,看到一辆出租车反响转弯停在路边.
l watched to see what was happening
'cause l had a feeling what would occur,
我看到有什么要发生了,因为我感觉有事要发生
'cause it's not a new thing.
这不是新鲜事了.
They pulled up right here
by this yellow fire hydrant
他们停在那个黄色的消防栓旁边
and dropped Carol off
and immediately pulled away.
把Carol放下然后迅速走了.
And as soon as they pulled away, she
walked out into the street about up to here.
当他们离开的时候,她走到了马路中间,大概这个位置.
She then walked all the way down to the
driveway down here, completely confused,
然后她走到了车行道的这个地方,整个人都糊涂了,
has no shoes on whatsoever
and just a hospital gown.
没有穿鞋子,只穿了医院的睡袍.
And those gowns are thin.
睡袍很薄.
That's when one of our staff members went
and asked Carol if she needed assistance
当我们的一个职工走过去 问Carol是否需要什么帮助
and found out that she was disoriented
and didn't know where she was.
发现她整个人分不清方向,不知道自己在哪里.
Kaiser Permanente in Bellflower hospital
had put her in a cab
Kaiser下属的风铃草医院的员工 把她放进了一辆出租车里
and directed them
to bring her to this drop-off point.
让他们直接把她送到病人待的地方.
But the names of the hospitals had been
taken off both bracelets before she arrived.
但是在到达这里之前 她两只手腕上的标注医院名字的被拿走了.
l have seen others that have come through
our doors who have lVs still in their arms.
我看到其他穿过我们大门的人手上都有身份标志.
(Moore) They told me that.
at their shelter alone.
他们告诉我.
over 50 patients
had been dumped there by hospitals.
有超过50名的病人被医院扔下了.
The options are few. We either open
the front door and let them out,
我们没有什么选择. 我们没有打开门让他们出去,
which is not the humane thing to do,
因为这十分不人道,
or we try to find someplace for them to go.
或者我们找个地方让他们去.
And right now,
skid row is the best bed in town.
现在,平民窟是这个镇上最好的待的地方.
(Moore) The night
before we were there.
在我们今晚过去之前.
the county hospital run by
the University of Southern California.
南加利佛尼亚大学， 国内最富有的一所私立学校.
one of the richest private schools
in the country.
经营的一所医院.
dumped another patient off on the curb.
在路边扔下了另外一个病人.
A woman unable to pay her hospital bill.
一个不能支付医药费的妇女.
- Do you know how you got here?
- ln the cab.
- 你知道你是怎么到这里的吗? - 坐出租车来的.
- ln the cab?
- From General Hospital.
- 出租车? - 从医院过来.
They gave him the voucher.
他们已经付了车费了.
He dropped me off there,
he actually forced me out of the car.
他把我丢在这里,事实上他是强迫我从出租车里出去的.
Ma'am, are you in pain right now?
Are you in pain?
夫人,你现在难受吗? 现在难受吗?
- Yes.
- ls there anything we can do?
- 是的.  - 我们能为你做点什么?
She, at this time, has broken ribs,
broken collarbone,
她,那个时候,肋骨断了,锁骨也断了,
and stitches that are not completely healed
她的侧面和头顶上,
across the top of her head
and on the side of her head.
还有没有完全缝合的伤口.
Now let me ask you, ma'am.
Before they dropped you off,
我来问你,夫人. 在我丢下你之前,
did they ask you
if you knew where you were going?
他们问过你是否知道自己去哪里吗?
No.
不知道.
They didn't ask you any questions
about your orientation,
他们没有问任何关于你的方位的问题,
or whether or not
you knew what was going on?
不管你是否知道接下来发生什么?
No, they just told me
to take care of myself.
没有,他们只是让我自己照顾好自己.
(Moore) May I take a minute to ask
a question that's been on my mind?
我能花一点儿时间问一个一直困扰我的问题吗?
Who are we?
我们是谁?
Is this what we've become?
这是我们应该变成的样子吗?
A nation that dumps its own citizens like
so much garbage on the side of the curb.
一个仅仅是因为公民付不起医药费.
because they can't pay
their hospital bill?
就把他们像垃圾一样丢在马路边,抛弃自己公民的国家?
I always thought. and believe to this day.
that we're a good and generous people.
我一直认为,直到今天还相信我们是高尚而且慷慨的人.
This is what we do
if somebody's in trouble.
这些就是我们在别人
Anybody gets sick,
we all get together and help.
遇到困难的时候所做的帮助.
(Moore) People with a good heart...
怀着一份热心的人...
(man #1 2) You feel like you're sacrificing,
but you get a blessing from doing this.
你觉得自己在牺牲一些东西,但是你得到别人的祝福.
(Moore) ...and a good soul.
...和一种精神.
We've got a lot of support and we're gonna
all keep working until we locate this child.
我们获得了很多的支持,我们会一直致力于帮助这些孩子.
(Moore) Neighbors quick to lend a helping
hand to anyone in their hour of need.
邻居会在任何时候向 需要帮助的人伸出援助之手.
l deliver meals to them,
but my life has been so blessed
我给他们送饭,我的生命得到了祝福
that this is just the least that l can do.
这只是我能做的一点事情.
(Moore) They say that you
can judge a society
他们说你可以通过它如何对待穷苦人民来判断一个社会
by how it treats those
who are the worst off.
来判断一个社会的好坏.
But is the opposite true? That you can
judge a society by how it treats its best?
但是这是相反的事实?  你可以通过它如何对待精英份子
Its heroes?
来评价一个社会?
(man #1 3) The firefighters and police,
rescue and recovery workers
消防员和警察以及救援人员
have responded with true heroism.
代表着真正的英雄主义.
lt was their initial heroism
that thwarted the objectives of the terrorists.
他们最初的英雄主义是阻止恐怖分子的目的.
Without regard, in many instances,
to their own safety and security.
没有受到尊敬,在很多时候牺牲了自己的安全.
- They truly are heroes.
- (man #1 4) We owe them everything!
- 他们是真正的英雄. - 我们欠他们太多了!
Here they are, the men and women who
have been on the front lines for New York,
我们在这里,那些为纽约,
and for all of us in America!
Tonight is dedicated to you!
为我们所有的美国人! 今晚为你献身!
5年后
9/11援救人员筹款活动
Don't forget about the raffles going on
over there - one dollar each.
不要忘了那边的抽奖活动,一美元一次.
l spent two and a half years down there.
我在那里干了两年半.
l got upper and lower
breathing problems.
我的呼吸出现了问题.
l need a double lung transplant,
but was diagnosed with pulmonary fibrosis.
我两边的肺需要移植手术,但是我又被诊断出肺纤维化.
l haven't slept in a bed in over five years,
l sleep on a chair with a blanket,
我已经五年没睡在床上了,我盖着毯子睡在椅子上,
because if l lay down l can't breathe.
因为我一旦躺下,我就无法呼吸了.
(Moore) There were hundreds
of rescue workers on 9/ 1 1
911事件后有超过一百名的营救人员
who were not city employees.
他们不是政府人员.
but rather ran down to Ground Zero
on their own to help out.
但是他们自愿去灾区帮助别人.
We need volunteers for first aid!
我们需要志愿者去帮助!
(Moore) And many developed
serious respiratory illnesses.
很多人患上了严重的呼吸疾病.
That's when the government said.:
当时政府这么说:"
''They're not our responsibility
because they weren't on our payroll. ''
这不是我们的责任,因为他们没有在我们的薪水册上."
John Graham is an EMT volunteer
from Paramus. New Jersey.
John Graham是 一名来新泽西Paramus的志愿急诊医士.
He was in Lower Manhattan
when he heard the planes hit.
当他听说世贸大楼被飞机撞击的时候 他正在下曼哈顿区.
and rushed over to help.
他立即冲到了现场.
He worked in the rescue effort
for the next few months.
接下来几个月他帮助救援工作.
but then had trouble
receiving benefits for his illness.
但是结果他自己得了那个疾病.
They just deny you for any reason.
lt's just a terrible waiting game.
他们用任何理由来否定你. 这只是一场可怕的等待游戏.
l really feel like
they're waiting for you to die.
我真的感觉到他们在等着你死.
lt's terrible.
l never thought that we would do this,
很可怕. 我从来没想过我们会这样做,
that the United States would do this.
美国政府会这样做.
(Moore) William Maher is a volunteer
member of New Jersey's fire service.
William Maher是新泽西的一名救火志愿者.
He spent two months
working near The Pile at Ground Zero.
他在911的废墟堆里工作了2个月.
recovering bodies or body parts.
and it deeply affected him.
收拾尸体和残余的部分,这深深地影响了他.
l'm experiencing
a lot of disturbing dreams,
我经历了很多令人不安的梦
or whatever you'd like to call them,
不管你怎么叫他们,
and it affected
what l was doing at night,
这影响到了我夜里的行为,
and unaware of it because l was asleep
我自己不知道,因为我睡着的时候
and l just kept
grinding and grinding my teeth.
就只是一直磨牙.
The upper fronts are damaged,
practically beyond repair,
我上面的牙齿磨损的很厉害,很难修复了,
because of my constant grinding
over the last three years.
因为我在过去3年里一直不停地磨牙.
l've been before a workers' comp board
already for the 9/1 1 volunteers' fund.
我之前住在工人待的地方试图 申请911志愿者的救济金.
l've been denied three times, and hopefully
l will go on my fourth appeal soon,
我已经被否定了3次,幸好我即将进行第四次的尝试
if l can get the necessary documentation.
如果我得拿到足够的文件.
(Moore) Of course.
there was a $50 million fund set up
当然,有五千万美元的救济金
supposedly to help rescue workers.
用来帮助救援人员.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the governor of New York, George Pataki.
女士们,先生们,纽约市市长,George Pataki.
(Moore) But the government.
like the health insurance companies.
但是政府像医药保险公司.
made it very difficult
for people to receive help.
使得人们很难得到帮助.
You have to have spent
a certain amount of time at Ground Zero,
你必须要在废墟区待上一段时间,
you have to be able to establish that.
你必须要有足够的经历.
You do have to file an affidavit
within the next year,
你必须在下一年有在废墟区工作的经验,
relating your work experiences
at Ground Zero.
来交一份陈述书.
And then, even with all of that,
it's not automatic.
即使这些条件都符合了,也不是自动的.
There is a presumption
when certain illnesses occur,
有一个假定,当疾病发生时,
but that presumption can be rebutted
by other medical evidence.
但是这个假定也可以被医疗证据反驳掉.
We think it is a very fair approach
that protects our heroes.
对于保护我们的英雄们， 我们认为这是一种非常直接的方式
l'm sorry.
抱歉
(Moore) Reggie Cervantes was
a volunteer medical technician on 9/ 1 1.
Reggie Cervantes 是“9/11”时的一名志愿医疗技师
Nothing makes it go away sometimes.
Not water, not cough medicine, anything.
有些时候根本没办法解决 水，止咳药，任何东西都没用
lt's just burning in my throat and irritated
and it just gets me to coughing.
它就像在我的嗓子里受到刺激一样烧了起来 然后咳嗽就接踵而至
Sometimes l have trouble breathing
'cause l can't catch my breath.
有时我甚至呼吸都困难 因为我几乎吸不到空气
(Moore) Reggie spent her days
at Ground Zero carrying bodies
Reggie在第一现场 负责搬运尸体
and treating other rescue workers.
还有照顾其他救援人员
My airway was totally burnt
that first week,
我的气管在那时的第一周 整个就像烧起来了一样
and l had trouble breathing by then.
之后我就感到呼吸困难
But we wanted to see
if we could dig anybody up alive,
但我们想看看是否还能挖出生还的人
we wanted to see if we had lost anybody,
if we were still missing somebody.
如果我们还有未救起的人的话 我们想看看是否还落下了生还者
l wanted to help.
l was trained for this.
我想要帮助他们 我为此接受了训练
You know, you see somebody
who is in need, you help 'em.
嗯，你看到有人需要帮助 然后伸出援助之手
(Moore) Reggie had difficulty
getting treatment.
Reggie在接受治疗上存在困难
Too sick to work and with no income.
虚弱而不能工作 还有没有收入来源
she was forced to quit her job.
她被迫辞职
and used her savings
to move her and her kids out of the city.
然后利用自己的积蓄 带着孩子们搬出了这座城市
lt's hard to figure out
how you're supposed to get help.
很难知道你应该怎么到帮助
We're trying to go about it the right way.
我们尝试着以正确的方式解决这件事.
But we're ignored.
但显然我们被忽略了
(Moore) But not everyone after 9/ 1 1
was ignored by the government.
但并不是每一个人在“9/11” 之后都会被政府部门忽略
We're now approaching the five-year
anniversary of the 9/1 1 attacks.
“9/11”五周年纪念离我们不远了
So l'm announcing today
that Khalid Sheikh Mohammed,
我今天宣布Khalid Sheikh Mohammed
Abu Zubaydah, Ramzi Binalshibh,
Abu Zubaydah、Ramzi Binalshibh
and 1 1 other terrorists in ClA custody,
还有其他11名在CIA监管下的恐怖分子
have been transferred to
the US naval base at Guantanamo Bay.
已被押送到了海军在关塔那摩湾的军事基地.
(man #1 5) On that island are some of the
world's most hardened enemy combatants.
那个岛上有这个世界上最坚毅的敌方战员
(man #1 6) These detainees are deadly
and include the 20th hijacker,
这些死刑犯都是致命的 包括了20名劫机犯
as well as a number of Osama bin Laden's
personal bodyguards
以及本・拉登的私人保镖
and others who had a direct role
in the September 1 1 attacks.
还有在“9/11”中扮演重要角色的一些罪犯
The kind of people held at Guantanamo
include terrorist trainers, bomb-makers...
在关塔那摩湾关押的人中 包括了恐怖分子的训练者、炸弹制造者...
Many of them have American blood on
their hands and are the elite of al-Qaida.
他们中的许多人手上都沾有美国民众的鲜血 他们都是al-Qaida组织的精英分子
lt seems to me we have an obligation
看起来我们有责任
to treat these individuals
as enemy combatants.
把他们当敌方战员来对待
(Moore) And then I learned
it wasn't all bad news at Gitmo.
之后我意识到这些并不是 来自关塔那摩所有的坏消息
(man #1 6) Detainees representing a threat
to our national security
那些威胁了国家的安全拘留者
are given access
to top-notch medical facilities.
可以享受到第一流的医疗设施
They have acute care 24 hours a day,
in which surgical procedures,
当他们在外科病房中时 有不间断的24小时的精细看护
everything can be performed right there
in the detainee camps.
在拘留犯看管所里应有尽有
This is the dental clinic,
or the health clinic.
这里是牙科诊所 或者是医疗诊所
We have a physical therapy department,
X-ray capabilities with digital X-rays.
我们有理疗部门 带有数字X光的X光射线设备
We have one single operating room.
我们有一个单独的手术室
Health personnel to detainee ratio
is one to four, remarkably high.
拘留犯中健康人员的比例是一比四 非常高
They do sick call on the blocks three times
per week, care for them there if they can,
我们每周进行三次会诊 尽量直接照看他们
or bring that detainee back to the clinic
to be seen there.
或者把他们带到医疗室去检查
Screening for cancer has taken place.
我们已经开始在那里对癌症进行检查
Colonoscopy is a procedure which
is performed there on a routine basis.
结肠镜检查在那里也成为了 每日的常规检查
We have diabetes,
high blood pressure, high cholesterol.
那里有糖尿病 高血压以及胆固醇偏高
We monitor the weight
and nutrition of the detainees,
我没对拘留犯的体重和营养状况进行检测
so that we can track those detainees
to make sure we see them frequently,
这样我们可以进行跟踪调查 来确定我们经常可以看见他们
monitoring their labs
and their overall health.
监视他们的实验室 以及他们的所有健康状况
Their medical attention... They get way
better medical treatment than l've ever had.
他们的医疗方式...  是我经历过最好的
- You think it's as good as most US HMOs?
- Certainly very similar and as good, sir.
－你觉得和美国的HMOs(商业医疗保险)一样好？ －非常相像，先生
(man #1 5) l leave with an impression
that healthcare there is clearly better
带着对保健措施非常好的印象我离开了
than they received at home,
至少比我在家能接受到的要好
and as good as many people receive
in the United States of America.
其他很多人在美国接受到的医疗保障一样
(Moore) Wow! So there is actually
one place on American soil
哇!那么在美国的土地上 至少有个地方
that had free universal healthcare.
具有全面的免费医疗保障
That's all I needed to know.
这就是我们所需要知道的
I went down to Miami. Florida.
我去了弗罗里达州的迈阿密市
got myself a boat.
给我自己弄了艘船
and loaded up Bill.
载上Bill
and Reggie and John.
Reggie还有John
John, welcome, sir.
John，欢迎你
And anyone else I could find who needed
to see a doctor and couldn't afford one.
还有其他所有我能找到需要看医生 却无力支付的人们
So many people showed up.
I had to get a couple extra boats.
这么多人都来了 我得再多弄几艘船来
And I called up Donna Smith from Denver.
who is now on nine different medications.
我打电话给丹佛的Donna Smith 她在接受9项不同的治疗
and asked her
if she'd like to come along.
我问她是否愿意独自来一趟
I figured she'd like to get out
of her daughter's basement for a while.
我得知了她很乐意从 她女儿的地下室里面出来散散心
All right, let's go.
好了，我们出发
你们要试图闯过去么？
Which way to Guantanamo Bay?
Can we go?
去关塔那摩湾怎么走？ 我们能去吗？
We're not going to Cuba!
We're going to America!
我们不是要去古巴！ 我们要去美国！
lt's American soil!
是美国的领土！
美国国土安全法禁止这部电影的制作人 展示他们如何到达的目的地
We made it.
我们成功了
There it is.
There's the runway.
在那里 河道在那里
That's the prison over there
where the detainees are.
那里就是关押拘留犯的监狱
- (Reggie) We're very close.
- Yeah, we're very close.
－非常接近了 －对，非常接近
The white building is the hospital, l think.
我想那座白色的建筑一定就是医院了
OK, let's go.
好吧，出发
(Moore) We commandeered a fishing boat
and sailed into Guantanamo Bay.
我们征募了一艘船 然后划进关塔那摩湾
As we approached the line in the water
between the American and Cuban side.
当我们接进水中的美国和古巴分界线的时候
we were told to be careful for mines.
有人告诉我们要小心水雷
Permission to enter.
l have three 9/1 1 rescue workers.
请求进入 这儿有三个“9/11”救援人员
They need some medical attention.
他们需要医疗检查
These are 9/1 1 rescue workers!
They just want some medical attention!
这里有“9/11”救援人员 他们需要医疗检查！
The same kind that al-Qaida is getting.
那些al-Qaida分子接受的医疗检查
They don't want any more than
you're giving the evildoers, just the same!
他们不需要 比你们给那些坏蛋更高级的治疗，就要一样的
Hello.
嗨
No one in the guard tower was
responding and then we heard a siren.
在看守塔上的人没有回答我们 然而我们听到了警报声
We figured it was time
to get out of here.
我们觉得是该离开这里的时候了
But what was I supposed to do with these
sick people and no one to help them?
但对这些病人该怎么办呢？ 没人来帮助他们
I mean. here we were stuck in some
godforsaken Third World country.
我是说，我们正处于荒凉的第三世界国家中
And communists. no less. When I was
a kid. these people wanted to kill us.
还有共产主义者 没错，我小的时候这些人就想杀了我们
What was I supposed to do?
我该怎么办？
( ''I'll See You in C-U-B-A''
by the Austin Lounge Lizards)
( ''I'll See You in C-U-B-A'' 演唱者Austin Lounge Lizards)
Excuse me, we're looking for a doctor.
ls there a doctor here in Cuba?
打扰一下，我们在找医生 古巴有医生吗？
Any doctors?
任何医生
那边墙角处有个医生
那边有家医院
那边有个药房
All in this one block?
都在这个街区？
都在这，是的
通常每个街区都有个药房
附近都有家医院
All right, thank you very much.
Thank you.
好的，非常感谢
(Moore) OK. OK. I know what you're
thinking. Cuba is where Lucifer lives.
好的，我知道你是怎么想的 古巴是撒旦(指卡斯特罗)待的地方
The worse place on Earth.
The most evil nation ever created.
地球上最糟糕的地方 已建立的国家中最邪恶的一个
How do we know that? 'Cause that's
what we've been told for over 45 years.
我们怎么知道的？ 因为这话我们已经听了45年了
A series of offensive missile sites
can be none other
一系列的攻击性导弹
than to provide a nuclear strike capability
against the western hemisphere.
只提供对西半球的核打击能力
l'm not gonna yield until Fidel Castro
allows freedom on the island.
我是不会屈服的，直到卡斯特罗 能让岛上存在和平
That's a...
You can count on it.
那是... 你们会有指望的
Put it in the bank.
把它放到银行里去
(Moore) It seems that
what really bugged us about Castro
看起来卡斯特罗 让我们感到麻烦的是
was that he overthrew
the dictator that we liked.
他推翻了我们支持的领导人的统治
And replaced him with a guy
we didn't like - himself.
然后另一个我们不喜欢家伙代替了前任领导人 就是他本人，卡斯特罗
And so now. after all these years.
one thing is clear -
现在，这么多年以后 有一件事情很清楚
the Cuban people
have free universal healthcare.
古巴人民有全面的免费医疗保障
They've become known as having not
only one of the best healthcare systems.
他们不仅仅由于具有 不止一个医疗保障系统而出名
but as being one of the most generous
countries in providing doctors
还有在提供医生方面的最慷慨的国家
and medical equipment
to Third World countries.
以及为第三世界国家提供医疗设备方面
In the US. healthcare costs
run nearly $7.000 per person.
在美国，医疗花费 人均为7.000美元
But in Cuba. they spend only $ 25 1.
但在古巴，只有251美元
And yet the Cubans are able to have
a lower infant mortality rate than the US.
还有在古巴婴儿的死亡率要低于美国
a longer average life span
than the United States.
人均寿命也要强于美国
They believe in preventive medicine.
他们相信预防性的药物
And it seems like there's a doctor
on every block.
看起来似乎每个街区都配有一名医护人员
Their only sin
when it comes to healthcare
他们唯一的过失就是医疗检查
seems to be
that they don't do it for a profit.
对于他们来说不是一份谋利的职业
Anybody need medication right now
from the pharmacy?
有人现在需要医疗吗？
- Are you the pharmacist?
- Yes.
－你是药剂师？  －是的
Do you have this?
你有这个吗？
- ls this one similar to yours?
- (Reggie) Yeah. lt's $1 20 in the US.
－和你的一样吗？ －对，这个在美国卖120美元
- This is $1 20 in the US?
- Yes.
－这个在美国卖120美元？ －对
那个多少钱？
3.20比索
- How much is that in American dollars?
- lt's like five cents.
－要多少美元 －5美分
- Five cents?
- Yeah. More or less.
－5美分？ －对，差不多
那有个医生
我把她的名字给你
让她给你
至少2个处方
Thank you very much.
Muchas gracias.
非常感谢 非常感谢
$1 20 is a lot of money
120美元是笔不小的数目
when you get $1 ,000 in social security
disability and need one or two a month.
当你只拿1000美元的社会残疾人保障金 却一个月需要一、两瓶的时候
Five cents here?
lt's like the biggest insult.
5美分？真是天大的笑话
lt just doesn't make any sense.
太不可思议了
lt doesn't make any sense.
真不可思议
l wanna fill a suitcase up
and go back home with it.
我想买一箱然后带回家去
(Moore) I took my group
of sick Americans to a hospital
我带着这些生病的国人去了一家医院
to see if they could get some care.
去看看我们能否会得到救助
They didn't ask for money
or an insurance card.
他们没有问我们要任何的钱或者是保险卡
姓名？
Just their name...
仅仅是他们的姓名
生日？
and date of birth.
还有出生日期
2月22日
That was the entire intake session.
这就是全部的手续
欢迎你们来这里
和其他病人一样
你们将得到最好的医疗护理
希望你们愉快地治疗
我们能做到的
我们都会全力做好
(Moore) Thank you very much
for doing this.
非常感谢你做的一切
I asked them to give us
the same exact care
我要求他们给我们一样的治疗
they give their fellow Cuban citizens.
就像给他们的古巴市民那样
No more. no less.
不多，也不少
And that's what they did.
那也是他们所作的
l'm Dr. Roque.
l'm an internal medicine specialist.
我是Roque医生 我是一名国内的医学专家
- John Graham.
- How are you feeling?
－John Graham －你感觉怎么样？
My lungs hurt. l have pain.
我的肺有问题，很痛
l get pretty severe nosebleeds at times.
我有时会大量鼻部出血
l get terrible headaches in the night,
我晚上会有剧烈的头疼
but l haven't been evaluated
for the sleep apnea for nine years.
九年来我没有接受过睡眠期无呼吸检测
- Yeah, l have...
- Many medications for lung problems.
－嗯，我有... －许多针对肺部的医疗
Almost every medication
for lung problems, l've got.
几乎所有针对肺部的医疗 我都接受过
After 9/1 1 , things have happened,
my teeth started falling out.
“9/11”之后 ，病症出现了 我开始掉牙
Because of certain conditions,
l was grinding.
由于某些原因 (睡眠时)我开始不自觉的磨牙
There's one test that they recommended
l take, it's about $5,000 to $ 7,000.
他们推荐我去接受一种测试 但那要花费我5000到7000美元
The dentist that l talked to,
it's like $1 5,000 or more.
我咨询的那个牙医 他告诉我花费15000美元或者更多
lt's two years l have no medical coverage,
so l can't go for the last part of the test.
两年来我没有接受任何医保 所以我没能完成测试的最后一部分
恩，不用担心， 每一项指标都会被仔细测试的
lt's OK, everything's gonna be OK.
Right?
没关系的，一切都会好起来的
Yes. l am so...
嗯，我非常的...
lt's so hard for me to digest
somebody saying it's free.
让我相信这一切都是免费的很难
Because 20 years of our lives
have been spent fighting.
因为20年来我一直在不停的抗争
So l am so grateful.
因此我非常的高兴
No, you don't need to say that.
不，不必那么说
- Thank you. Thank you.
- OK.
－非常的感谢你，非常 －好的
Come on, don't cry.
Everything's gonna be OK, right?
振作起来，不要哭 一切都会好起来的，不是吗？
- Thank you.
- At least what we can do, right?
－谢谢 －至少我们能做到的
古巴只是加勒比海中 一个资源匮乏的小岛
我们尽一切努力去保障人们的健康
而美国却不是这样
为什么我们能而你们不能？
需要注意的是
因为一个国家越富有
就更应该照顾好它的人民
(Moore) Reggie was diagnosed with
pulmonary and bronchial problems.
Reggie接受了肺部和支气管的检查
The Cuban doctors gave her
a treatment plan to follow back home.
古巴医生给了她 一个回家后的治疗计划
along with some of those
five cent inhalers.
当然还有那些单价五美分的吸入器
William Maher received a number
of treatments on his neck and his back.
William Maher接受了很多颈部和背部的治疗
Having ground down his teeth for
three years due to post-traumatic stress.
医生去掉了他三年来由于外伤后压力过大 而损坏的牙
he left Cuba with a new set of teeth.
他带着两排全新的牙齿离开古巴
After a series of tests
on his heart. lungs. blood and stomach.
在他接受了一系列关于 心脏、肺、血液和胃部的测试后
John now knew
what his ailments were.
John现在才知道他的病痛究竟是什么
He was given a strict plan to follow.
plus a number of treatments
他拿到了一份必须严格执行的计划 他还接受了一系列的治疗
and was feeling better
than he had in years.
他现在感觉比以前好多了
The Cuban doctors were able to take
Donna off five of her nine medications.
古巴医生可以去掉 Donna九项治疗的五项
And with a correct diagnosis.
gave her a treatment plan
通过正确的测试给了她一个治疗计划
to help her live a more normal life.
使她能够过上正常人的生活
When firefighters
and paramedics in Havana
当消防人员 护理人员到Havana时
heard that the 9/ 1 1 rescue workers
were in town.
得知了“9/11”救援人员 在城里
they invited them over
to one of their firehouses.
他们邀请这些人去他们的一个消防站
And so. on our last day there.
因此，在我们在那里的最后一天
as we arrived. they stood at attention
当我们到达时，他们注视着站在那里
because. they said.
they wanted to honor the heroes of 9/ 1 1.
因为，他说他们相向“9/11”的英雄们致敬
你们来访我们非常荣幸
我们都记得911恐怖袭击的那一刻
给我们带来极大的悲伤
从人道的角度看
我们应该帮助进行救援工作
我们也是那么做的
世界的消防队员是一家
Si. somos familia. Y los hermanos
que perdimos en las Torres Gemelas
是的 我们是一家 911中牺牲的消防员都是我们的兄弟
se sintio en el mundo completo.
他们仍然活在我们心中
The brothers we lost on 9/1 1
was felt around the world.
911中我们失去的兄弟 仍然活在我们心中
- Mis hermanos.
- 我们是兄弟 - 我们是兄弟
Don't hesitate to hug a brother.
不要犹豫，快了拥抱他们吧
lt's very important for them to wear
the SCBA so they don't end up like me.
对于他们来说佩戴SCBA(正压式空气呼吸器)很重要 这样他们就不会像我一样了
- They're lungs.
- These tanks.
－它们是呼吸器 －这些罐子
SCBA. Self-Contained
Breathing Apparatus.
SCBA(正压式空气呼吸器) 带有呼吸装置
Tenemos una reserva tambien en el carro.
我们的车上也提供这个
Es un placer poder venir aqui.
很高兴能来这
Esto es lo unico
que tenemos nosotros. . .
这是我们唯一能做的
F-F-F.
F－F－F
Three Fs.
三个“F”
这是消防队的工作服，
送给你们做纪念
(Moore) If this is what can happen
between supposed enemies.
如果这是可能成为敌人之间的故事
if one enemy can hold out his hand
and offer to heal.
如果你的敌人能伸出援助之手
then what else is possible?
那么还有什么不可能的!
That's when I heard
that the man who runs the biggest
我听到的那个运营
anti-Michael Moore website
on the internet
最大的反Michael Moore的网站
was going to have to shut it down.
要将网站关闭
He could no longer afford to keep it up
because his wife was ill
他无法在继续运营下去 因为他的妻子病了
and they couldn't afford to pay
for her health insurance.
他们负担不起医疗保险的费用
He was faced with a choice of either keep
attacking me or pay for his wife's health.
他要面对的是继续反对我或者 花钱给他妻子治病的选择
Fortunately. he chose his wife.
可喜的是，他选择了他的妻子
But something seemed wrong
about being forced into such a decision.
但是看起来被迫作出
这样的选择似乎有些不妥
Why. in a free country. shouldn't he
be able to have health insurance
为什么在如此自由的国度中 居然不能有医疗保险
and exercise his First Amendment right
to run me into the ground?
正确的操作他的“第一修正案” 让我感到很困惑
So I wrote a check for the $ 1 2.000
he needed to keep his wife insured
所以我写了一张12000美元的支票 使他能够支付他妻子的医疗保险
and in treatment.
and sent it to him anonymously.
以及治疗 然后以匿名方式寄给了他
His wife got better
and his website is still going strong.
他的妻子身体好了起来 他的网站也依旧很火
It was hard for me to acknowledge
that in the end.
这令我到最后也不得其解
we truly are all in the same boat.
我们真的都是一条船上的人
And that. no matter what our differences.
无论我们多么的不同
we sink or swim together.
我们一起漂浮或者沉没
That's how it seems to be
everywhere else.
就像其它任何地方的人一样
They take care of each other.
no matter what their disagreements.
他们彼此互相照顾 无论他们的分歧是什么
You know. when we see a good idea
from another country. we grab it.
当我们发现其他国家一个好的想法时  我们就效仿
If they build a better car. we drive it.
如果他们造了一辆较好的车 我们就去驾驶
If they make a better wine. we drink it.
如果他们酿出了一瓶更好的葡萄酒 我们就一饮而尽
So if they've come up with
a better way to treat the sick.
那么如果他们有更好的来医治病人的方法
to teach their kids.
来教育他们的后代
to take care of their babies.
去照顾他们的孩子
to simply be good to each other.
简简单单的彼此厚待
then what's our problem?
那么我们还有什么问题
Why can't we do that?
我们为什么不能做到
They live in a world of ''we. ''
not ''me. ''
他们生活的世界强调的是“我们” 而不是“我”
We'll never fix anything
until we get that one basic thing right.
我们从来不忙于做决定 直到我们弄清楚最基本的问题
And powerful forces
hope that we never do.
有权力的势力也不希望我们那样做
And that we remain the only country
in the western world
我们因此便成为了西方世界独特的国家
without free universal healthcare.
没有免费的全民医疗保障
You know. if we ever did remove
the chokehold of medical bills.
如果我们能够摆脱
那些令人窒息的医疗帐单
college loans. day care.
大学贷款，日常护理
and everything else
that makes us afraid to step out of line.
还有其他一切使我们怕做出越轨之事的东西
well. watch out.
那么，要当心了
'cause it'll be a new day in America.
因为美国的新时代就要来临
In the meantime.
与此同时
I'm gonna go get the government
to do my laundry.
我要让美国政府帮我去做些干洗
-=北理FTP联盟字幕组=-
作品  本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=BiTUNiON SuBTiTLe GROUP=-   翻译：ycx198 yxy871211 doctor0623  maths4513 filippolu GarF1eLd 校对：xkimi
( ''Alone Without You''
by The Nightwatchman)
( ''Alone Without You'' 演唱者The Nightwatchman)
( ''Ce Monde Absurde''
by Claude Francois)
( ''Ce Monde Absurde'' 演唱者Claude Francois)